[{"question":"<p><strong>The earth is a ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["planet","star","meteorite","solar flare"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The smallest planet in the solar system is...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Uranus","Neptune","Venus","Mercury"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Our planetary system is made up of ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["milky way","the earth, moon and the sun","nine planets and the sun","all stars that are visible at night"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>All the following planets orbit the sun in anti-clockwise direction except ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["earth","pluto","uranus","mars"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The associated relief feature of a block mountain is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["caldera","lopolith","rift valley","anticline"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A line joining places of equal sunshine is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["isobar","isotherm","isoshine","isohel"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Cirrus, cumulus, stratus and nimbus are types of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fog","frost","rain","cloud"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a member country of ECOWAS?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Liberia","Cameroon","Ghana"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria is located on longitude<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15<sup>o<\/sup>","73<sup>o<\/sup>","15<sup>o<\/sup>","8<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not part of the ocean floor?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["deep sea plain","Lombolo","trench","continental"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the likely occupation in an area occupied by scattered cultivation?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fishing","farming","quarrying","lumbering"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a method of surveying?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["harchuring","plane table","chain","theodolite"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The compass traverses survey method cannot easily be used in all but of the following area<\/strong><\/p>","options":["enclosures","built up areas","open areas","area with vegetation cover"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Rainfall and temperature graphs are usually represented by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["flow line maps","dot maps","bar and line graphs","divided circles"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a proof of the earth's sphericity?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["circum-navigation","sunrise and sunset","solar eclipse","driving poles on level ground"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following are pairs of rocks and what they metamorphose to. Which one is wrongly paired?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Limestone-> marble","Shale-> schist","Granite-> quartzite","Clay-> slate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In an earthquake, it is the vibrations caused by the ______ waves that produce the most damage<\/strong><\/p>","options":["surface","body","stress","collision"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following volcanoes have not erupted in historic time?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mt Fujiyama","Mt. Cameroon","Mt. Kilimanjaro","Mt. Pinatubo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The smallest planet in the solar system is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Uranus","Neptune","Venus","Mercury"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Twilight is the period of time between<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sunset and sunrise","the setting of the sun and the rising of the moon","the rising of the moon and daybreak","daylight and midnight"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is true during an eclipse of the moon<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the moon's shadow is cast on the earth","the earth's shadow is cast on the sun","the sun comes between the earth and the moon","the earth comes between the sun and the moon"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following planets has the longest orbit round the sun?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Jupiter","Mars","Neptune","Saturn"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major distinguishing characteristic of plutonic rocks is that they contain<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pyroclasts","fine grains","bedding planes","large crystals"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following rock types is formed by the cooling of molten rock within the earth's crust?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sandstone","granite","basalt","shale"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>On which days of the year are night and day the same length?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["22nd March and 22nd September","22nd June and 22nd December","31st December and 31st June","Midsummer day and midwinter day"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sedimentary rocks are easily recognized in fields because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["they form rounded hills","they occur in horizontal layers","they occur in layers","they are folded"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following factors is most important for the rapid increase in world population during the 20th century?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["rapid increase in birth rate","the abolition of slave trade","rapid decrease in death rate","migration of people"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"}]